<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

	<ClickToJumpToProblem>Click t' jump t' problem</ClickToJumpToProblem>

  
  
  <NeedSawmill>Need sawmill</NeedSawmill>
  <NeedSawmillDesc>Ye need some kind o' sawmill t' chop logs into more versatile wood planks.\n\nBuild a HAND SAWMILL or an ELECTRIC SAWMILL.</NeedSawmillDesc>

  <PoorMood>Poor mood</PoorMood>
  <PoorMoodDesc>These colonists be in a poor mood and may have a soft mental break at any time:\n\n{0}\nCheck these colonists' Thoughts tab t' see what's botherin' them.</PoorMoodDesc>

  <TerribleMood>Terrible mood</TerribleMood>
  <TerribleMoodDesc>These colonists be critically stressed and may have a hard - and potentially violent - mental break at any moment:\n\n{0}\nCheck these colonists' Thoughts tab to see what's bothering them</TerribleMoodDesc>

  <ColonistNeedsRescue>Colonist needs rescue</ColonistNeedsRescue>
  <ColonistsNeedRescue>Colonists need rescue</ColonistsNeedRescue>
  <ColonistsNeedRescueDesc>  These colonists be incapacitated on th' ground:\n\n{0}\nSend another colonist t' rescue them and carry them aft t' bed.\n\n(To rescue, select another colonist, then right click on th' victim 'n select Rescue.</ColonistsNeedRescueDesc>

  <BuildARoom>Build a room</BuildARoom>
  <BuildARoomDesc>A room be composed 'o separate wall pieces wit' a door.\n\nUse t' ARCHITECT menu at t' bottom port o' t' screen t' designate where you want thin's built. Once you designate somethin' t' be built, your colonists will do t' work when they can.</BuildARoomDesc>

  <NeedDefenses>Need defenses</NeedDefenses>
  <NeedDefensesDesc>Ye've be here some time 'n have probably been seen. Scurvy pirate raids gunna start soon.\n\nYe should prepare defenses.\n\nBuild some turrets.</NeedDefensesDesc>

  <NeedDoctor>Need doctor</NeedDoctor>
  <NeedDoctorDesc>These colonists need medical care, but ye have no healthy colonists assigned as doctors.\n\n{0}\nAssign a healthy colonist to th' Doctor work type. If left untreated, wounds may never heal properly 'n may become permanent.</NeedDoctorDesc>

  <NeedMiner>Need miner</NeedMiner>
  <NeedMinerDesc>You have designated some rocks to be mined, but no colonist has the Mining work type.\n\nAssign a colonist the Mining work type.</NeedMinerDesc>

  <NeedWarden>Need warden</NeedWarden>
  <NeedWardenDesc>Ye have a prisoner, but no colonist has th' Warden work type.\n\nAssign a colonist th' Warden work type.</NeedWardenDesc>

  <LowFood>Low food</LowFood>
  <LowFoodDesc>Ye only have {0} nutrition worth 'o food in storage. 'tis be dangerously low.\n\nGrow, buy, find, or murder some food.</LowFoodDesc>

  <NeedColonistBeds>Need colonist beds</NeedColonistBeds>
  <NeedColonistBedsDesc>Ye have more colonists than ye have colonist beds. Someone gunna lack a place to sleep.\n\nEither make more beds, or change a prisoner bed to a colonist bed.\n\nIf ye have no resources, sleepin' spots be free 'n can be placed instantly.</NeedColonistBedsDesc>

  <HunterLacksWeapon>Hunter lacks weapon</HunterLacksWeapon>
  <HunterLacksWeaponDesc>A colonist be assigned as a hunter but has no weapon. They will not hunt 'til they be carryin' a weapon.\n\nTo reduce injury, we recommend givin' them a ranged weapon.</HunterLacksWeaponDesc>

  <Starvation>Starvation</Starvation>
  <StarvationDesc>These colonists be starvin':\n\n{0}\nGet them some food. ye'll need a food source like a nutrient paste dispenser 'n some food to feed it. Also, make sure they're not drafted.</StarvationDesc>

  <Exhaustion>Exhaustion</Exhaustion>
  <ExhaustionDesc>These colonists be exhausted 'n need rest:\n\n{0}\nGet them some rest. They'll need a bed marked fer colonist use. Also, make sure they're not drafted.</ExhaustionDesc>

  <NeedFoodHopper>Need food hopper</NeedFoodHopper>
  <NeedFoodHopperDesc>Ye have a nutrient dispenser wit' no hopper next to it.\n\nTo work, paste dispensers must draw from an adjacent hopper filled wit' raw food.\n\nBuild a hopper adjacent to th' dispenser.</NeedFoodHopperDesc>

  <BuildingNeedsPower>Buildin' needs power</BuildingNeedsPower>
  <BuildingsNeedPower>Building's need power</BuildingsNeedPower>
  <BuildingsNeedPowerDesc>These power-usin' buildin's be totally disconnected from all possible power sources:\n\n{0}\nConnect them to a power generator or battery.</BuildingsNeedPowerDesc>
  <AndMore>and more</AndMore>

  <NeedMealSource>Need meal source</NeedMealSource>
  <NeedMealSourceDesc>You have no way of preparing proper meals from raw food.\n\nBuild a nutrient paste dispenser or a cook stove.\n\n(It cannot be in a prison cell, otherwise colonists cannot use it.)</NeedMealSourceDesc>

  <NeedHomeRegion>Need home region</NeedHomeRegion>
  <NeedHomeRegionDesc>You need to define a HOME REGION where your colonists will clean, extinguish fires, and repair things.\n\nDefine a home region using the ZONES section of the ARCHITECT menu.</NeedHomeRegionDesc>

  <NeedBatteries>Need batteries</NeedBatteries>
  <NeedBatteriesDesc>You only have solar generators and no batteries. This means you'll lose power every time the sun goes down.\n\nBuild a battery or two to get you through the night.</NeedBatteriesDesc>

  <NoTradingCapacity>No trading capacity</NoTradingCapacity>
  <NoTradingCapacityDesc>You have no way of trading with passing ships.\n\nBuild a comms console.</NoTradingCapacityDesc>

  <BrawlerHasRangedWeapon>Brawler has ranged weapon</BrawlerHasRangedWeapon>
  <BrawlerHasRangedWeaponDesc>One of your colonists has the Brawler personality trait, but is carrying a ranged weapon. This will make them very unhappy.</BrawlerHasRangedWeaponDesc>

  <ShieldUserHasRangedWeapon>Shield user has ranged weapon</ShieldUserHasRangedWeapon>
  <ShieldUserHasRangedWeaponDesc>One of your colonists has a personal shield and is carrying a ranged weapon. They will not be able to fire their weapon through the shield (except at targets who are already touching them).</ShieldUserHasRangedWeaponDesc>

  <NeedResearchProject>Need research project</NeedResearchProject>
  <NeedResearchProjectDesc>You have the equipment to do research but have not selected a project.\n\nOpen the research menu and select a project.</NeedResearchProjectDesc>
  
  <NeedDump>Need dump</NeedDump>
  <NeedDumpDesc>You have marked {0} to be hauled, but the colonists have nowhere to take it.\n\nDesignate a stockpile and set its storage settings to accept {0}.</NeedDumpDesc>

  <NeedGrave>Need grave</NeedGrave>
  <NeedGraveDesc>There is a dead body laying on the ground and nowhere for your colonists to take it.\n\nBuild a grave or a dumping zone and set their storage settings.</NeedGraveDesc>

  <ColonistsIdle>{0} colonists idle</ColonistsIdle>
  <ColonistsIdleDesc>These colonists are wandering idly:\n\n{0}\nYou should probably find them something productive to do.</ColonistsIdleDesc>

  <HaltedConstructions>{0} constructions are missing materials</HaltedConstructions>
  <HaltedConstructionsDesc>These constructions are missing materials:\n\n{0}\nYou should probably make required materials available for your colonists.</HaltedConstructionsDesc>

  <ColonistNeedsTreatment>Colonist needs treatment</ColonistNeedsTreatment>
  <ColonistNeedsTreatmentDesc>These colonists need medical treatment. Without it, they may die of their wounds, or their wounds may become permanent.\n\n{0}\nTreat them by sending them to a medical bed.\n\n(First, assign a medical bed by selecting it and toggling it into a medical bed. Then, select the wounded colonists and right-click on the medical bed to make them a patient.)</ColonistNeedsTreatmentDesc>

  <AlertHypothermia>Hypothermia</AlertHypothermia>
  <AlertHypothermiaDesc>These colonists are suffering from hypothermia.\n\n{0}\nMake sure their clothing is appropriate for the season and that indoor spaces are properly heated.</AlertHypothermiaDesc>
  
  <ColonistsAwaitingMedicalOperation>{0} colonists await medical operation</ColonistsAwaitingMedicalOperation>
  <ColonistsAwaitingMedicalOperationDesc>These colonists await medical operation:\n\n{0}\nMake sure you have all necessary medical tools and a free doctor available.</ColonistsAwaitingMedicalOperationDesc>

  <FireInHomeRegion>Fire!</FireInHomeRegion>
  <FireInHomeRegionDesc>There is a fire in the home region.</FireInHomeRegionDesc>

  <PawnsWithLifeThreateningDisease>Severe illness</PawnsWithLifeThreateningDisease>
  <PawnsWithLifeThreateningDiseaseDesc>People are at risk of death because of severe illness:\n\n{0}\nMake sure that they get the best medical possible.</PawnsWithLifeThreateningDiseaseDesc>
  <PawnsWithLifeThreateningDiseaseAmputationDesc>People are at risk for death because of severe illness:\n\n{0}\nIf possible, consider amputating or replacing infected limbs in order to keep colonists alive.</PawnsWithLifeThreateningDiseaseAmputationDesc>

</LanguageData>
<NoMedicineDesc>You have no medicine left in storage.\n\nBuy more medicine from traders.</NoMedicineDesc>
<BilliardsNeedsSpace>Billiards needs space</BilliardsNeedsSpace>
<HunterHasShieldAndRangedWeaponDesc>One of your hunters is using a ranged weapon and wearing a shield belt which prevents shooting at range.\n\nThey won't be able to hunt unless the shield is removed.</HunterHasShieldAndRangedWeaponDesc>
<HunterHasShieldAndRangedWeapon>Hunter has shield and ranged weapon</HunterHasShieldAndRangedWeapon>
<LowMedicineDesc>You only have {0} medications left in storage.\n\nBuy more medicine from traders.</LowMedicineDesc>
<NeedWarmClothesDesc1All>All of your colonists will lack warm clothes when the cold season comes.</NeedWarmClothesDesc1All>
<AlertTatteredApparel>Tattered apparel</AlertTatteredApparel>
<AlertTatteredApparelDesc>These colonists are wearing tattered apparel, which is making them sad:\n\n{0}\nGet them some apparel that isn't so badly damaged.\n\nYou can tailor apparel at a tailoring table, or buy it from traders.</AlertTatteredApparelDesc>
<ImmobileCaravanDesc>One of your caravans is immobile because it carries too much.\n\nYou can make the caravan mobile again by abandoning some items in the ITEMS tab.</ImmobileCaravanDesc>
<PatientsAwaitingMedicalOperationDesc>These patients await medical operation:\n\n{0}\nMake sure you have all necessary medical tools and a free doctor available.</PatientsAwaitingMedicalOperationDesc>
<LowMedicine>Low medicine</LowMedicine>
<ImmobileCaravan>Immobile caravan</ImmobileCaravan>
<StarvationAnimals>Animal starvation</StarvationAnimals>
<NeedWarmClothesDesc1>At least {0} of your colonists will lack warm clothes when the cold season comes.</NeedWarmClothesDesc1>
<NeedWarmClothesDesc2>The outdoor temperature is going to reach {0}.\n\nYou can tailor warm clothes at the tailoring bench, or buy them from traders.</NeedWarmClothesDesc2>
<BreakRiskMajor>Major break risk</BreakRiskMajor>
<NeedJoySource>Need joy source</NeedJoySource>
<AlertUnhappyNudityDesc>These colonists are nude and not happy about it:\n\n{0}\nGet them some clothes.\n\nYou can tailor apparel at a tailoring table, or buy it from traders.</AlertUnhappyNudityDesc>
<FireInHomeAreaDesc>There is a fire in the home area.</FireInHomeAreaDesc>
<BreakRiskMinorDesc>These colonists are in a poor mood and may have a minor mental break at any time:\n\n{0}</BreakRiskMinorDesc>
<NeedJoySourceDesc>Your colonists need to fulfill their joy need, but you haven't built any joy sources.\n\nHelp them by building a horseshoes pin, chess table, or other joy source.</NeedJoySourceDesc>
<NeedWarmClothes>Need warm clothes</NeedWarmClothes>
<BreakRiskMajorDesc>These colonists are in a very poor mood and may have a major mental break at any time:\n\n{0}</BreakRiskMajorDesc>
<BreakRiskExtremeDesc>These colonists are critically stressed and may have an extreme (and possibly violent) mental break at any moment:\n\n{0}</BreakRiskExtremeDesc>
<StarvationAnimalsDesc>These colony animals are starving:\n\n{0}\nGet them some food.</StarvationAnimalsDesc>
<BreakRiskExtreme>Extreme break risk</BreakRiskExtreme>
<BreakRiskDescEnding>Check these colonists' Needs tab to see what's bothering them.\n\nTo make colonists feel better, you can do things like make them fancy meals, give them more joy hours per day and nicer joy objects, place them in beautiful environments, have them drink and smoke, and much more.</BreakRiskDescEnding>
<AlertUnhappyNudity>Unhappy nudity</AlertUnhappyNudity>
<BilliardsNeedsSpaceDesc>One of your billiards table is adjacent to an obstruction that will prevent colonists from using it.\n\nA billiards table needs clear space around it on all sides to be usable.</BilliardsNeedsSpaceDesc>
<PatientsAwaitingMedicalOperation>{0} patients await medical operation</PatientsAwaitingMedicalOperation>
<FireInHomeArea>Fire!</FireInHomeArea>
<BreakRiskMinor>Minor break risk</BreakRiskMinor>